Gursheen Chawla

613-620-2378 | gursheen1436@gmail.com | Ottawa, ON K1K 1X4

SUMMARY

Junior Web developer with experience developing the frontend or backend. Recently completed a development certification course at Code Youth. Also, acquired a Cybersecurity credential from University of Ottawa to maximize the understanding of digital threats in web development. Previous experience includes work with the customer support team handling small businesses in a B2B set up.

SKILLS

- Web development
- Software Testing
- Support Operations
- Scrum (PSM-1)

- Data Organization and Research
- Cybersecurity
- Microsoft Office

EXPERIENCE

Researcher, CODE YOUTH, October 2021 – Present (VOLUNTEER)

- Research the application and scope of frameworks/programming languages used in Web Development.
- Research on different online websites who offers courses for web development, gaming, and mobile development.

Support Specialist, AGSOFT, May 2018 - September 2020 (FULL TIME)

- Represented organizations in various Sales and Support activities.
- Received inbound phone calls from customers to provide first-level support and remotely troubleshooted issues with service or customer accounts.
- Cultivated client relations and drove retention by effectively authoring and updating technical documentation and manuals.
- Worked with supervisors via live chat to address customer inquiries or technical issues beyond scope of expertise.
- Documented and updated case notes for each customer and work order. Maintained compliance with established and updated policies and procedures with minimal supervision.

Mathematics Instructor, DIPS, March 2016 - October 2016 (FULL TIME)

- Instructed 120 students per semester and developed all goals and objectives.
- Distributed and posted course syllabus and answered student questions regarding standards, material, grading and progression at the beginning of semester.
- Posted periodic grades and final grade rosters in the school grading system with supporting documents according to established deadlines.
- Modified instructional methods and strategies to teach students with diverse needs.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Web Development Bootcamp

Code Youth, Ottawa, December 2021 - Present

Master of Computer Applications

Lovely Professional University, India June 2015 - 2017

Bachelor of Computer Applications

Guru Nanak Dev University, India May 2012 - 2015

CERTIFICATIONS

Advanced Information and Cyber-Security Leadership

University of Ottawa, November 2021 – Present